Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Stereographs 1850-1964 (Bulk 1860-1900) PR 65
New-York Historical Society
- Geographic, 1850-1964
  - New York--Saratoga Springs--Hotels -- Grand Hotel, [1870s] (Box 51)
    Grand Hotel, Saratoga Springs: exterior views; views of the piazza, including guests seated there.
  - New York--Saratoga Springs--Hotels -- Grand Union Hotel, [1865-1880] (Box 51)
    Identifier:PR-065-0580
    Grand Union Hotel, Saratoga Springs: primarily interior views showing the office, the parlor, the dining room; the piazza from above, showing visitors seated there; the front of the hotel, including views of shops on the lower level; the park at the rear of the hotel, with lanterns strung for the "Illumination," and a fountain.
  - New York--Saratoga Springs--Hotels -- United States Hotel, [1870-1885] (Box 51)
    Identifier:PR-065-0581
    United States Hotel, Saratoga Springs: the front of the hotel, including the piazza; the rear of the hotel, including views of "cottage row" and visitors seated in the gardens and on the rear piazza; fountain in the garden; interior views including the parlor and the dining room.
  - New York--Saratoga Springs--Lakes and scenery, [1865-1885] (Box 51)
    Identifier:PR-065-0582
    Scenery around Saratoga: Saratoga Lake, showing steam yachts and sailboats, view of the lake from Leslie's grounds, with an Adirondack-style summer house in foreground, and the grand stand at the Intercollegiate regatta, 1874; Geyser Falls and Geyser Lake; shooting gallery at Moon's Lake House; ruins of the Marvin House; an fanciful summer house in Frank Leslie's grounds; a gypsy camp with wagon, and campfire; Blue Mill Bridge, Radarossown Creek, Saratoga Springs.
  - New York--Saratoga Springs--People, [1865-1880] (Box 51)
    Identifier:PR-065-0583
    People at Saratoga Springs: group portraits of men and women at various unidentified sites; man and girl in the garden of a hotel; Champion boat crew, Hank, Josh, Gill, Ellis, and a fifth man, possibly their coach or manager; men and women raking hay in the park.
  - New York--Saratoga Springs--Springs, [1860-1885] (Box 51)
    Identifier:PR-065-0584
    Springs at Saratoga Springs, including Congress, Columbian, Champion, Empire Eureka, Geyser, Hawthorn, High Rock, Saratoga Star, United States, Washington, and an unidentified spring; most views show spring house and visitors, some have interior views, including a view of the stained-glass interior of Congress Spring, Geyser Spring shooting straight up, and the rock at High Rock Spring; Champion Springs shooting up, and a winter view showing the spring frozen.
  - New York--Scarsdale, 1862 (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0585
    Pophams Mills, showing river and partial mill structure.
  - New York--Schenectady, [1880] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0586
    View of the railroad depot, Schenectady, N.Y.
  - New York--Schroon Lake, [1870] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0587
    Men and women boating on Schroon Lake.
  - New York--Sharon Springs, [1860-1875] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0588
    Magnesia Springs at Sharon Springs, N.Y., including view of group in carriage in front of the springs.
  - New York--Silver Lake, [1884-1891] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0589
    Silver Lake: steam yacht, and dog in rowboat; main entrance to Camp Wesley, group standing near the gate.
  - New York--Skaneateles Lake, [1880s] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0590
    Sailboat and small house at the edge of Skaneateles Lake, N.Y.
  - New York--Springville, 1885 (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0591
    Springville: crowd gathered around Prof. Squire's hot air balloon on July 4th.
  - New York--Starucca Creek, [1860-1875] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0592
    Starucca Creek: views of the scenery, including the Starucca viaduct, man fishing (?) and two men and a boat.
  - New York--Sterling Forest, 1962 (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0593
    views in Sterling Forest Gardens: waterfall and pump; archway covered with roses; tuberose begonias; design in colored gravel; water lilies; ducklings; a peacock; "Slice of Time" rock formation with waterfall.
  - New York--Syracuse and vicinity, [1860-1900] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0594
    Syracuse and vicinity: general views from tower of Syracuse Savings Bank; an early view of the Syracuse Savings Bank, along the banks of the canal; the canal and buildings along it; canal boat loading salt; Fourth Presbyterian Church; "the Home"; view from the farm of William J. Bass; views at the New York State Fair, including the race track, the Syracuse Chilled Plow Company exhibit, and other halls; Chlorine Springs and salt works; views at the Oneida Community, showing members posing on the lawns, women in bloomers, large buildings beyond; doll house in the shape of a building with a clock on top, figures of workers inside.
  - New York--Tarrytown, [1865-1959] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0595
    Tarrytown: general view; Sunnyside, home of Washington Irving, one view showing house in snow, and a view of a nearby brook; old mill, and nearby house, used by Washington as headquarters; residence of Gen. Webb; Dutch Church, and the bridge where Icabod Crane was said to be pursued by the headless horseman, Sleepy Hollow; the Andre Monument; Jay Gould's estate Lyndhurst: a series of views of the estate, including views toward the Tappan Zee, the conservatory, an interior view of the art gallery, and views of children including a Kindergarten class, children attending a party, playing games and watching a magic show; girls on their way to sewing school, at Lyndhurst.
  - New York--Taughannock Falls, [1870s] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0596
    Views at Taughannock Falls, including visitors standing at the base of the falls.
  - New York--Thousand Islands, [1870-1885] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0597
    Views in Thousand Islands: islands and the Saint Lawrence River; general view of Alexandria Bay; summer houses in the park; hotels and cottages with guests out front; balloon ready for ascension by H.D. Squire, in front of Thousand Island House; summer houses; a bridge on Sport Island; steam yachts and other boats; steamboat at Thousand Island Park dock; group portraits including group of young African Americans (students?) and a white family; partridge in a nest; King bird's nest with eggs.
  - New York--Ticonderoga, [1870-1885] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0598
    Ticonderoga: views of the ruins of Fort Ticonderoga, including interior view of the magazine; general view of the village of Ticonderoga.
  - New York--Trenton Falls, [1856-1875] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0599
    Views at Trenton Falls: rapids and waterfalls, and rocky river banks; snowy scenes with icicles; visitors; the Trenton Falls Hotel.
  - New York--Troy, [1870-1885] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0600
    Troy: general views of the town from Warren's Hill; N. 2nd Methodist Episcopal Church; Church of the Ascension; American House; an office block; a fire station [?]; a bridge; the Polytechnic Institute; a factory with a railroad siding; a bridge and waterfall on Postenkill Creek; unidentified mill building; large classical building, with opera poster nearby; Hudson River Railroad station; unidentified waterfall by a Troy photographer.
  - New York--Union Springs, [1870] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0601
    Union Springs: group of women and a girl seated on a porch a the top of steep stairs; carriage gate and opening mechanism at the entrance to the Springs.
  - New York--Walton, [1865] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0602
    Covered bridge on the Delaware River, Walton, N.Y.
  - New York--Warsaw, [1870] (Box 52)
    Identifier:PR-065-0603
    Wyoming valley from Warsaw Railroad depot, train standing at the station.
  - New York--Watervliet, [1870] (Box 52)
    PR-065-0604
    Wagons and carriages line drive leading to the Shaker village at Watervliet.
  - New York--Watkins Glen, [1860-1900] (Box 53)
    PR-065-0605
    Watkins Glen: views in the Glens, including rocky gorges, waterfalls, ladders, bridges and paths; sightseers, including man fishing; frozen waterfalls and icicles; view of a glen, with a camera visible at left; Glen Mountain House; ruined mill in Freer's Glen; general view of Watkins, with Seneca Lake, beyond; train standing at Erie Railway coal dumping pier on Lake Seneca near Watkins; train crossing the iron bridge on the Syracuse, Geneva & Corning Railroad, and Hogs Back Gorge.
    110 items
  - New York--Weedsport, [1870] (Box 53)
    PR-065-0606
    Weedsport Skirt and Dress Co.'s exhibit showing hoop skirts or bustles hanging on display [copy photograph].
  - New York--West Point, [1856-1900] (Box 53)
    PR-065-0607
    Views at the United States Military Academy at West Point, and vicinity: views on the Hudson River, including a dock and steamboat at the landing, Naval Academy Fleet; Hudson River sloops on the river; Garrison Ferry; general views of the academy; the mess hall; barracks; railroad station; views of cadets, including in full dress, standing at attention, marching, receiving scholarships, drilling with cannons, light artillery drill with caissons, volley fire drill, skirmish line drill; sleeping out of doors; the U.S. Military Academy Band; Trophy Point, showing cannons and a view of the Hudson; tents on the grounds of the Academy; ruins of Fort Putnam; groups of civilians visiting; Civil War and other monuments; statue of John Sedgwick Indian Falls; Buttermilk Falls, Cozzens Hotel and Kilpatrick's House; Highland Falls.
    87 items
  - New York--Whitehall, [1860-1875] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0608
    Whitehall: views on Lake Champlain, including boaters, canal boats in Whitehall harbor; general views of the town showing the canal, businesses, homes, and a fence-lined road; view of a hotel (?) coated with ice; businesses along Canal Street; other views showing businesses and bridges along the canal.
  - New York--Yonkers, [1865-1959] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0609
    Yonkers, N.Y.: general view of Yonkers from the Palisades; waterfront, including views of the town, sloops, rowboats and piers; Cross County Shopping Center; South Broadway north from Hudson St., savings bank, right; Getty Square; City Hall; Philipse Manor.
  - North Carolina, [1870-1903] (Box 54)
    Identifier:PR-065-0610
    North Carolina: man and wagon on mountain road near Chimney Mountain post office; Laurel Creek near the French Broad River; rock formation called Lovers Leap, above the road along French Broad River; young women near a chapel, St. Mary's School, Raleigh; man putting cotton in cotton screw; young African-American woman selling lightwood in front of Rufus Morgan's photography gallery, Morgantown; African-American men and women gathering crude turpentine.
  - North Dakota, [1873-1900] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0611
    North Dakota: Bismarck: general views showing train yard; street scenes, one showing street thronged with wagons; businesses including a clothing store, feed store, hardware store; men sitting on the porch of the Northern Pacific Depot; the Merchant's Hotel; Signal station and headquarters of [NJ?] Telegraph; Fargo: Old and New 1st National Bank; looking west on Front Street, showing National Bank and other businesses; general view of cavalry quarters, Fort Abraham Lincoln; view down Missouri from Fort Lincoln; supply store, Jamestown; Grand Forks Railroad bridge of the St. Paul and Manitoba Railroad, looking east; flood at Grand Forks; Northern Pacific Railroad bridge near Mandan; Northern Pacific Railroad bridge across the Missouri near Bismarck; Northern Pacific locomotive with snow plow; views on wheat farms of the Red River Valley, including plowing and harrowing.
  - Ohio, [1870-1901] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0612
    Ohio: Canton: street scene, from the bridge; tomb of President McKinley; Columbus: carriages in front of the capital building; Dayton: Soldiers home, including group of veterans on a porch discussing the pension bill; South Street, showing businesses, telephone poles; snowy Ohio street in Marietta; log cabin birthplace of Gen. U.S. Grant in Point Pleasant; steamboat landing from the observatory of the Put-in-Bay House, showing lake, island and steamboats; small ship on Lake Erie; group at Blowing Springs near Steubenville; steamboat and bridge, Wilmington; covered bridge over the Rocky River.
  - Ohio--Cincinnati, [1865-1900] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0613
    Cincinnati: scenes on the Ohio River at Cincinnati, including steamboats, the Cincinnati - Covington Bridge (including view of entrance), the Cincinnati - Newport Bridge, and including views of Cincinnati from Covington, Kentucky; public landing and Spencer House; the jail; the Tyler Davidson Fountain showing setting in small park; large unidentified mausoleum.
  - Ohio--Cleveland, [1870-1896] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0614
    Cleveland: general views including a view of the West Side Hill, with homes, factories, and a general view from Detroit Street showing railroad along waterfront; Standard Oil works, showing tanks and chimneys; the steamboat "Pearl" moored near a building with sail loft and wholesale grocers advertised on the side; a balloon, ready to ascend, with crowd gathered around it; miniature lake and rustic bridge in Cleveland Monumental Park; Pres. Garfield's tomb at Lake View Cemetery, guards posted in front.
  - Oklahoma, [1870] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0615
    Will Soule's "photo shanty" at Fort Sill, with Satanta and band of Kiowas in foreground.
  - Oregon, [1867-1902] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0616
    Oregon: primarily views on the Columbia River including the Garrison and the blockhouse at the Cascades, a fish wheel, train passing the "Pillars of Hercules," railroad siding at the Dalles, with the Cascade foothill beyond, train and steamboat at landing at the Cascades, huge log raft on the river; men and fish weir on the Clackamas River; horse-pulled wheat combines; glaciers on Mt. Hood.
  - Pennsylvania, [1865-1903] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0617
    Pennsylvania: Rev. Dickey's church in Allegheny; train wreck near Bellefonte, June 11, 1878, showing ruined cars, and what appears to be a collapsed bridge; women seated on rocks along the Brandywine; children crossing footbridge in Bryn Mawr, along the line of the Pennsylvania Railroad, falls on Buckhill Creek, photographer's tent in the foreground; coal being delivered to a breaker, boys picking slate in a coal breaker; Caldeno Falls; Forest House at Cherry Run; Long Bridge, a covered bridge at Columbia; train passing through ice gorge arriving at Coxton; factory near Fairview, men on cupola; view from the cupola of the factory, farm fields and small buildings; horse-drawn streetcar, Germantown in the distance; view south to Round Top from the Gettysburg Battle field, cannons and monuments in foreground; view of a painting of a farm, paper mill and surroundings in lower Heidelberg Township; Female Seminary, Hollidaysburg; steel works, Homestead; view up the Lackawaxen depicting the river, canal and with man in stove-pipe hat in the foreground; bridge over Jack's Creek near Lewistown; Soldiers and Sailors Monument in Lancaster; Marshalls Falls; icy scenes in the glen in Pike's County, including huge icicles and a frozen waterfall; a 90-foot long, red-hot steel beam in steel works in Pittsburgh; covered bridge over the Delaware at Portland; men at Table Rock, West Falls, and a view on the Rumbling Run, including the photographer' s wagon, near Pottsville; Scranton: men and women in garden in front of Italianate home, two locomotives built by the Dickson Mfg. Co. for the Delasare and Hudson Canal Company, Albany and Susquehana Railroad department; looking west in Susquehanna, Erie R.R. locomotive shops, center; large barrel-vaulted dining hall, Starucca House, Susquehanna Depot; Washington's Headquarters at Valley Forge; a view on the Schuylkill River; first opening of the anthracite coal field of Pennsylvania (made in 1807), 4 miles below the city of Wilkes-Barre.
  - Pennsylvania--Pennsylvania Railroad, [1860-1903] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0618
    Views along the Pennsylvania Central Railroad: tracks, trains, bridges, sidings, tunnels, men with hand cars, docks at Lake Erie, scenery along the way including creeks, a view in a cut on the Old Portage Road, sightseers and groups long the line, hotels at Altoona and at a resort in the Alleghennies; locations include the Juniata River, Huntington, Lewiston Narrows, the line near Tyrone, bridge near Manor, crossing the Susquehanna, Kittanning Point; interior view of wheel machine shop.
  - Pennsylvania--Canals, [1870] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0619
    Canals in Pennsylvania: view of water flowing over lock gate; Dutchman's Lock, in Beaver County; view from the Weigh Lock of the Delaware and Hudson Canal in Wayne county, showing several bloats tied in the locks; horses on edge of canal, boat in middle, homes at right, unidentified town.
  - Pennsylvania--Catawissa Creek, [1865-1875] (Box 54)
    PR-065-0620
    Catawissa Creek and Railroad views: Susquehanna River opposite Catawissa; man rowing near Catawissa Island; bridge over Catawissa Creek; Sayerman's Saw Mill, Catawissa Creek, with large trestle in background; bridge under construction on the D.H. and W. R.R.; Bunker Hill Cut with train in the distance, girl in foreground; Veiled Falls; Aqueduct over Fishing Creek; bridge on North Branch Canal; rowboat on Fishing Creek in front of the aqueduct crossing it.
  - Pennsylvania--Delaware River, [1860-1883] (Box 55)
    PR-065-0621
    Delaware River: primarily views in the Delaware Water Gap, including views of the river and mountains, waterfall at "Rebecca's Bath," the railroad tracks running along the river, hotels including the Water Gap House, with porches and balconies all around and a view from the balcony, Cataract House, Lovers Retreat, boaters, including man in scull on river.
  - Pennsylvania--Johnstown Flood, 1889 (Box 55)
    PR-065-0622
    Aftermath of the Johnstown Flood and Fire, May 31, 1889: destroyed buildings; rubble strewn areas, including view of man posing as victim; wreckage of the Pennsylvania Railroad Day Express; broken dam on the Reservoir on the South Fork; Sandyville Cemetery filled with debris; Woodvale Jail, where it landed after being carried downstream; the stone bridge and burned debris; streets filled with debris; the wreckage of the iron works; tents erected for the flood victims; men recovering a body; Conemaugh Boro Fire Department, with overturned engine.
  - Pennsylvania--Lehigh Valley and Mauch Chunk, [1867-1887] (Box 55)
    PR-065-0623
    Views in the Lehigh Valley, and of Mauch Chunk: general views of Mauch Chunk, including railroad and Lehigh Canal, Mount Pisgah from the depot, river and buildings including a church in the foreground; Lehigh Coal and Navigation Co.'s chutes, with boats lined up for loading under a bridge; log rafts on the Lehigh Canal, footbridge in middle ground; canal in the Mauch Chunk narrows; inclined planes to bring coal down to the canal; switch back passenger train with passengers; Mt. Pisgah Plane, looking up, and looking down, including the car, view on the summit; Mansion House, including interior view of dining room; Mt. Jefferson Plane; Panther Creek Plane, looking up, and looking down; Moore's Falls; Terrace Falls, Glen Onoko; group posing by the rapids near Mauch Chunk; in the crater of burning mines; coal mine opening; coal breaker.
  - Pennsylvania--Oil region, [1860-1903] (Box 55)
    PR-065-0624
    Views in the Pennsylvania Oil Region, primarily views of oil derricks, including the Drake Well, the first oil well (1859, near Titusville), refineries, storage tanks, shipping in barrels on barges and by railroad tank car, oil gushers; pumping oil, oil refinery and tank fires, removing tools from wells, Little Giant engine, and a view of a man sitting on a boiler or engine with a "For sale cheap" sign on it; engines of an inclined Plane at Oil City; boy and young women bending in ditch near oil tanks, view labeled "Oil dipper"; The Boyd Farm, including the Boyd House; U.S. Hotel in Petroleum Centre; a small ferry at the Noble Well; railroad bridges over Oil Creek; Kinzua Bridge near Alton, "the highest bridge in the world"; men on the cars of a small elevated railroad; train at Union depot at Oil City; the Oil Exchange; saloon and reading rooms; buildings with sign reading "Brevoort" probably a hotel or boarding house, garden in the foreground; Stewart's residence; women on the porch of the Young residence; man in a wagon up to its hubs in mud; men and women posing in front of petroleum company offices locations including Edenburg, New London, Oil City, Petroleum Centre, Rouseville, Summit City, Tidioute, Trunkeyville.
    98 items
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia, [1870] (Box 55)
    Identifier:PR-065-0625
    Philadelphia: statue of William Penn in the courtyard of the Penn Hospital; Academy of Music; Arch Street theatre; Egyptian-style entrance to Laurel Hill Cemetery; horse-omnibuses in front of the N.Y. depot, 31st and Market; Mercantile Library.
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Bridges, [1870-1885] (Box 55)
    Identifier:PR-065-0625:
    Bridges in Philadelphia: the railroad bridge over the Schuylkill in Fairmount Park; Girard Avenue Bridge in the park; Callowhill Street Bridge, showing upper deck, cast-iron [?] supports; Cannon Street bridge, showing supports in the form of classical columns, and the Cannon Street terminus; Chestnut Street Bridge; Schuylkill Suspension Bridge, including view from the tower; bridge to Lansdowne Island and steamboat landing.
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Carpenter's Hall, [1870] (Box 56)
    Identifier:PR-065-0627
    Carpenter's Hall, Philadelphia, site of the U.S. Constitutional Convention.
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Centennial -- Grounds, 1876 (Box 56)
    Identifier:PR-065-0628
    Grounds at the Centennial Exhibition: general views from a top buildings, and the Observatory at Georges Hill depicting the lay-out of the fair, buildings, the lake, gardens, and fair-goers; street-cars on Elm Avenue at Fair entrance, carriages and omnibuses with Main building beyond; the hand and torch from the Statue of Liberty; a rustic gazebo; art gallery and railroad station; the Bartholdi fountain; a gate in a wooded area; bridges in Lansdown Valley; workers with wheel barrows and tools.
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Centennial -- Washington Carriage, 1876 (Box 56)
    Identifier:PR-065-0629
    George Washington's carriage harnessed to four white horses.
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Centennial -- Buildings, 1876 (Box 56)
    Identifier:PR-065-0630
    Buildings at the Centennial Exhibition: photographs of drawings or prints of Brazilian Commissioners building; Pennsylvania Railroad exhibit, depicting locomotive 1 of the Camden and Amboy Railroad; man in the cab of a B & O railroad locomotive; Old Abe" the live Wisconsin war eagle (carried in the War of Rebellion); Brewers' Hall; diorama depicting "King cotton and Louisiana" as an old couple with dog and cat, all made of cotton; Swedish school house, including interior; women in colonial costume outside the Log Cabin; Zoo Garden, Lion and Tiger house, and Rhesus monkey from Calcutta; Board of Finance building, showing intricate fretwork; Tufts soda fountain.
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Centennial--Buildings, Agricultural, 1876 (Box 56)
    Identifier:PR-065-0631
    Agricultural Hall, Centennial Exhibition: photographs of a rendering or a print of the building; interior view of exhibits, including a view when the hall is empty, general views, a windmill, a fountain, a Laplander and a reindeer.
  - Pennsylvania--Philadelphia--Centennial--Buildings, Art Gallery, 1876 (Box 56)
    Identifier:PR-065-0632